<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
	<name>Ecotech</name>
	<author>Sepphoris,NightmareCorporation</author>
	<supportedVersions>
		<li>1.5</li>
	</supportedVersions>
	<modDependencies>
	</modDependencies>
	<loadAfter>
	</loadAfter>
	<packageId>SA.Ecotech</packageId>
	<description>Mod Version: 1.0 (last updated @ 2.19.2024, ~4:00PM PST)

====================

A mod that introduces the ability to grow weapons and defenses in your garden, rather than machining them together.

Currently introduces terraweapons, which only require a green thumb to plant, and patience to grow. They are just as effective as fabricated weapons, giving you a 100% all-natural, viable alternative to your colony defenses.

However, terraweapons require highly fertile soil, take a significant amount of time to grow, and will wither over time.

This was originally is intended to provide decent weapons and equipment during a tech-limited, magic playthrough. No more relying on just bows!

More additions, such as other weapons, turrets, traps, and even armor will come over time!

====================

Latest Minor Update:
-

Latest Major Features and Changes:

-Tribal Colonies gain access to Terraseed knowledge immediately, due to this mod being intended as a total alternative to mechanical weapons. Industrial+ colonies will needs to pour significant time into understanding this exclusive tribal power.

-New Terraweapon: Prima Turret, a short-range turret that requires fertile soil instead of electricity.

-New Terraweapon: Prima Seedburster, an organic ballistic launcher.

-New Terraweapon: Royal Hyperstem, which is the first in a new line of Terraweapons, and can only (currently) be bought (seeds will come later once more weapons are made; colonies using Ideology can aqcuire it via relic)

-Added Surge Seed research, which unlocks seeds for constructed/building-based equipment (like turrets and traps).

-Added a teaser research for future additions.

-Stake Caster is now an entry weapon.

-Simplified a couple researches; entry researches cost slightly more, but provides more weapons, and will provide more over time.
Be aware these changes might impact early research progress. Any errors referencing them are one-time, and can be safely ignored.

-Please report balancing and bug issues on the workshop page!

</description>
</ModMetaData>